<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Creating card keywords">
     	<p>Card keywords are words, numbers or symbols that Mingle uses to create automatic links in cards and wiki pages. 
     		When you're editing a card or wiki page and you add any of these keywords, Mingle will automatically convert them to links.</p>
    	
    	<example>Your project has a card keyword definition of <markup>#</markup> 
    		If for instance, you would like the description for a card to contain a link to card number 123. 
    		Type: <markup>#123</markup> in the description to create a hyperlink to card 123.</example>
    	
	<hint>Choose card keywords based on the terminology that your team uses to describe cards, e.g. bug, defect, story, requirement, task, risk. 
		At a minimum, it is a good idea to include card keywords that match the card types you create in card properties. 
		If in doubt, it is better to include more card keywords than you will probably use.</hint>
    	
    	<p>When you type card keywords in Mingle (e.g. when editing a card description), always type the keyword followed by the card number, 
    		e.g. <markup>#123</markup> or <markup>card 123</markup> It's irrelevant whether or not you add a space.</p>
    	
    	
	<section title="How to create and update card keywords" file="create_card_keywords" />
	<section title="Using card keywords in source repository messages">
		<p>One of Mingle's strengths is the ability to link source commit messages to specific cards. This means you can link source versions to a bug, story or user requirement.</p>
       	<p>Using the example in the procedure above, if you type <markup>#123</markup> in a commit message, Mingle automatically creates a link to card number 123. When you are editing card number 123, you will also see the source version and commit message in the card's History tab.</p>
		<p><screenshot alttext="Card history - source commit link" src="resources/images/card_history_source_commit.png" /></p>
    	<p>In the <tab>History</tab> tab for Card 1 above, you can see that Revision 937 addressed some aspect of this card (story 1). Clicking the <link>Revision 937</link> link would take you to the <tab>Source</tab> tab where you could see all source files changed for that revision.</p>
    	
		<note>To use this feature, you must have successfully <cref topic="setup_source_repository_integration">integrated your source repository</cref> with Mingle.</note>
	</section>    	
	<section title="How to check whether your card keywords pick up card numbers in existing commit messages" file="testing_card_keyword_source_control_integration" collapsed="true" />
 </topic>


