<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Easy chart for Pie">
    <p>Pie charts are used to show groups of data in proportion to, or as a percentage of, the whole data set. They’re useful in project management to track the statuses of work towards a milestone, the break-up of the defect backlog by severity, the progress of completion of a feature etc. Check out our <cref topic="ec_pie_charts#ec_sample_piechart">sample pie charts.</cref></p>
        <screenshot alttext="Example pie chart" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_status.png" />
    <strong><p>CREATE A PIE CHART</p></strong>
    <p>To create a pie chart on a page or a card, follow these steps:</p>
    <bullets>
        <item>In the editor, click on the Pie Chart button.</item>
        <item>In the Easy Charts form, start by selecting the data that will go into your pie chart. This is similar to the filters you use to make various views in Mingle.</item>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart Section1" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_section1.gif" />
        <p>Click on <i>Proceed to Step 2</i> when you’re done with this step.</p>
        <item>Next, build the chart.</item>
        <p>Select the property of the cards that will group them into smaller sets and choose how you want to determine the size of each slice of the pie.</p>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart Section2" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_section2.gif" />
        <p>Click on <i>Proceed to Step 3</i> when you’ve finished this step.</p>
        <item>Customize how you want the chart to look. You can select a size, a title, where the legend is positioned, and whether you want the labels to represent percentages or whole numbers.</item>
        <item>Click on Insert to complete the chart and insert it into the page or card.</item>
        <item>You can interact with the completed chart. Hovering over the slices will show you the last updated ten cards that belong in each slice. Clicking on a slice takes you to a full list of all cards in the slice.</item>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart interaction" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_interaction.gif" />
        <p>You can also add or remove slices by interacting with the legend.</p>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart legend interaction" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_legend_interaction.gif" />
    </bullets>
    <strong>Notes</strong>
    <bullets>
        <item>You can use project variables in your chart setup. For instance, if you’d like the pie chart to represent work for the current release at any point of time, you can do so without having to update the chart each release!</item>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart using project variable" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_using_project_variable.gif" />
        <item>If you’re inserting a pie chart into a card description, you can refer to the card itself in your chart setup by selecting THIS CARD as a property value. For instance, if you want a pie chart in a Feature card to represent the status of all cards that belong to that feature, use Feature is THIS CARD in the filters.</item>
            <screenshot alttext="Pie chart using this card" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_using_this_card.gif" />
    </bullets>
    <p>
        <strong>CUSTOMIZE USING MQL:</strong>
    </p>
    <p>You can build or further customize a pie chart using Mingle Query Language. Here’s a sample MQL snippet:</p>
    <markup>
        pie-chart 
        data: SELECT Feature, COUNT(*) WHERE Type = Story
    </markup>
    <p>Some additional customizations you can set up in MQL are:</p>
    <bullets>
        <item>AS OF</item>
        <item>FROM TREE </item>
        <item>THIS CARD.Property</item>
        <item>Use relationship operators on non-numeric properties (where ‘Due Date’ is greater than ‘Release Date’)</item>
        <item>Custom chart width and height</item>
        <item>Custom colours</item>
    </bullets>
    <topic id="ec_sample_piechart" title="Sample pie charts">
    	<p><strong>Feature completion:</strong></p>
    		<screenshot alttext="feature completion" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_feature_completion.png" />
    	<p><strong>Workload:</strong></p>
    		<screenshot alttext="workload" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_workload.png" />
    	<p><strong>Iteration status:</strong></p>
    		<screenshot alttext="iteration status:" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_iteration_status.png" />
    	<p><strong>Features in a release:</strong></p>
    		<screenshot alttext="feature in release:" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_feature_in_release.png" />
    	<p><strong>Defect severity:</strong></p>
    		<screenshot alttext="defect severity:" src="resources/images/ec_piechart_defect_severity.png" />
    </topic>
</topic>