<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Modifying or deleting project variables">
	<section title="Navigate to the project variables page..." collapsed="true">
		<steps>
			<item><cref topic="signing_in_and_out_of_mingle">Sign in</cref> to Mingle as a project administrator and open the project (if you're not already working in the project).</item>
			<item>
				<p>Click the <tab>Project admin</tab> tab.</p> 
				<screenshot alttext="Project admin tab" src="resources/images/project_admin_tab.png" />
				<p>Mingle displays the <strong>Project settings</strong> page.</p>
				<note>if you are logged in as a project team member, Mingle displays the <strong>Team</strong> page.</note>
				<screenshot alttext="Project admin menu - Project variables link" src="resources/images/project_variables_link.png" />
			</item>
			<item>
				<p>Click the <link>Project variables</link> link.</p>
				<p>Mingle displays the <strong>Project variables</strong> page with all project variables setup for this project.</p>
			</item>
		</steps>
	</section>
	<screenshot alttext="Project variables page" src="resources/images/project_variables_page.png" />
	<section title="Modify a project variable...">
		<subsection title="Open the Edit project variable page...">
			<p>To modify a project variable, click on the <link>Edit</link> link to the left of the project variable name</p>
			<p>Mingle displays the <strong>Edit project variable</strong> page.</p>
		</subsection>
		<screenshot alttext="Edit project variable dialog" src="resources/images/project_variable_edit_dialog.png" />
		<subsection title="Renaming a project variable...">
			<p>Type a <strong> new Name</strong> for the project variable.</p>
			<p>This is the name which will identify the variable wherever it is used in the project, it should be as succinct and descriptive as possible.</p>
			<p>The name should not be blank, should not contain <![CDATA["'&', '=', '#', '[' or ']'"]]> characters, and must be less than 40 characters in length.</p>
			<p>Mingle will display how the project variable name will look - all project variable names are enclosed in parenthesis, e.g. (variable)</p>
			<hint>While it is possible to use the same name for both a project variable and a card property, it's probably less confusing to avoid doing so.</hint>
			<bullets title="Effect on pages">
				<item><cref topic="working_with_pages">Mingle pages</cref> and <cref topic="creating_charts_and_tables_in_pages">tables/charts</cref> that reference the renamed project variable will no longer work. 
					The MQL syntax will not be changed, so you will need to manually alter any affected pages to alter references to the new project variable name.</item>
			</bullets>
			<hint>
				<p>A fast way to find all of the pages which use the project variable in MQL is to use the <cref topic="mingle_search">Mingle search</cref>.</p> 
				<p>Simply type in the old name of the project variable e.g. "some project variable" and hit the <button>Search</button></p>
				<p>Mingle will show all pages referencing the project variable - you can then open each of these pages for editing and make the appropriate changes.</p>
				<p>Note that if your project variable name is a common word or phrase - you may get some additional pages that contain that word outside of MQL statements.</p>
			</hint>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Changing the type of a project variable...">
			<p>Select a <strong>new type</strong> for the project variable.</p>
			<warning>Changing the type of a project variable is effectively the same as deleting it and creating a new one with the same name. 
				See <strong>The effects of deleting a project variable</strong> below to understand the impact of changing the type of a project variable.</warning>
			<bullets title="available types:">
				<item><strong>Text</strong> - any text value</item>
				<item><strong>Numeric</strong> - any numeric value</item>
				<item><strong>Selected from team list</strong> - any project team member</item>
				<item><strong>Date</strong> - any valid date</item>
				<item><strong>Card</strong> - a reference to any card of the specified type</item>
			</bullets>
			<screenshot alttext="Update project variable confirmation page" src="resources/images/project_variable_update_warning.png" />
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Change the value of a project variable ">
			<p>Enter or select the <strong>new value</strong> you want to assign to the project variable.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Change which card properties are linked to the project variable...">			
			<p>The project variable will only be available in filter conditions, transitions and MQL queries for properties that it has been explicitly linked to.</p>
			<note>Only properties which have the same data type as the project variable will be shown in the list</note>
			<bullets title="Effects:">
				<item><strong>Transitions</strong> - any transition which used the project variable to set a property which is no longer linked to that project variable will be deleted.</item>
				<item><strong>Favorites and Tabs</strong> - any favorites or tabs which use the project variable to filter a property which is no longer linked to that project variable will be deleted.</item>
				<item><strong>Pages</strong> - any MQL statement which use the project variable as part of a condition on a property which is no longer linked to that project variable will no longer work.</item>
			</bullets>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Save your work...">
			<p>Click on the <link>Save project variable</link> link to save the project variable</p>
			<screenshot alttext="Save project variable link" src="resources/images/save_project_variable_link.png" />
		</subsection>
	</section>
	<section title="Delete a project variable...">
		<p>To <strong>delete a project variable</strong>, click on the <link>Delete</link> link to the left of the project variable name</p>
		<p>If there are any transitions which reference the project variable, Mingle will display the <strong>Delete project variable</strong> confirmation page</p>
		<screenshot alttext="Delete project variable confirmation page" src="resources/images/project_variable_delete_warning.png" />
		<p>Review the confirmation message, and if you want to continue click on the <link>Continue to delete</link> link to permanently delete the project variable.</p>
		<subsection title="The effects of deleting a project variable...">
			<bullets title="Card properties using the project variable">
				<item>There is no direct impact on card properties which are associated with the project variable.</item>
			</bullets>
			<bullets title="Card transitions">
				<item>Any <cref topic="card_transitions">card transitions</cref> which assign the project variable to a card property will be deleted</item>
			</bullets>
			<bullets title="Favorites and tabs">
				<item><cref topic="favorites_component">Favorites</cref> that include the deleted property as a display column or in a <cref topic="filter_list_by_component">filter condition</cref> will be deleted</item>
				<item>Any <cref topic="creating_tabs_from_favorites">tabs</cref> based on those favorites will also be deleted</item>
			</bullets>
			<bullets title="Pages">
				<item><cref topic="working_with_pages">Mingle pages</cref> and <cref topic="creating_charts_and_tables_in_pages">tables/charts</cref> that reference the deleted project variable will no longer work. 
				The MQL syntax will not be changed, so you will need to manually alter any affected pages to remove references to the deleted project variable.</item>
			</bullets>
			<hint>
				<p>A fast way to find all of the pages which use the project variable in MQL is to use the <cref topic="mingle_search">Mingle search</cref>.</p> 
				<p>Simply type in the name of the project variable e.g. "some project variable" and hit the <button>Search</button></p>
				<p>Mingle will show all pages referencing the project variable - you can then open each of these pages for editing and make the appropriate changes.</p>
				<p>Note that if your project variable name is a common word or phrase - you may get some additional pages that contain that word outside of MQL statements.</p>
			</hint>
		</subsection>
	</section>
</topic>
