<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Quick Project Setup">
	<section title="Here are the basics to get you up and running with Mingle!">
    <p>Mingle projects are where you store information about the projects you are working on. Mingle projects are very flexible and powerful. Mingle projects are composed of structured information, known as <cref topic="explore_mingle_topic_whats_a_card">cards</cref>, and a powerful <cref topic="working_with_pages">Mingle page</cref>. Both cards and pages can contain attached information. <cref topic="source_tab">Source code</cref> can be <cref topic="setup_source_repository_integration">associated</cref> with a Mingle project. Additionally, daily conversations can be stored in Mingle as <cref topic="murmurs">Murmurs</cref>. All of this information can then be linked together, providing an truly integrated collaboration environment for your team.</p>
    <p>To gain these benefits, you must first create a Mingle project and set it up so that it matches the way you work.</p>
		<note>
			<p>This section assumes you've already <cref topic="configuring_a_database_for_use_with_mingle">configured a database</cref> for your <cref topic="mingle_onsite">Mingle onsite</cref>, 
                and <cref topic="completing_the_mingle_configuration_wizard">completed the configuration wizard and setup the first user</cref>.</p>
			<p>The first user is the Mingle administrator and he/she has the necessary permissions to complete all of these steps.</p>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section title="Step one - Create a new project">
		
		You can either create a new project or create a project from a template. For the quickest project set-up we suggestion creating a card from a template. 
		
		<subsection title="Creating a new project from template" file="creating_a_project_from_template" />
	</section>
	<section title="Step two - Customize your project">
		<p>The Mingle project templates include relevant project settings, project reporting and sample cards. You can use these as a basis for <cref topic="customizing_projects">customizing your project</cref>. 
        From within your new project, customize project settings by clicking the <tab>Project admin</tab> tab.</p>
		<screenshot alttext="Project admin tab" src="resources/images/project_admin_tab.png"/>
		<p>There are several project settings you can configure. These are conveniently grouped under the various heading you see on the sidebar.</p>
		<subsection title="Card types" id='quick_project_setup_card_types' collapsed="true">
			<p><cref topic="card_types">Card types</cref> are the different kinds of things you would like to track in a project. Various kinds of projects would setup their own card types. A project which is purely in maintenance mode might have very different types of cards (bugs, issues, enhancements etc...) than a project which is under active development (story, bug, risk, UI issue etc...). Each card type can have its own set of properties. Customize card types by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Card types</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Card properties" collapsed="true">
			<p>Cards are the basic units you use to manage projects in Mingle. <cref topic="creating_card_properties">Card properties</cref> are how you define, sort, group and manage cards based on your project's workflow. 
                Each card property has one or more values that represent a card's current status. Customize card properties by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Card properties</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Card transitions" id='quick_project_setup_card_transitions' collapsed="true">
			<p><cref topic="card_transitions">Card transitions</cref> let you define your team's workflow, and you use transitions to forward work to various team members at different stages of the project lifecycle. 
                Card transitions place links on cards that match certain card properties. Clicking these links updates cards according to the card properties you specify. 
                They are used for completing common actions such as closing a bug or marking a user story as complete. Customize card transitions by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Card transitions</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Card trees" collapsed="true">
			<p><cref topic="creating_a_new_card_tree">Card trees</cref> allow you to define a hierarchy of parent-child relationships between any card types. 
                These relationships can be viewed graphically, as a <cref topic="tree_view">tree view</cref> or <cref topic="hierarchy_view">hierarchy view</cref>, and cards can easily be added and moved around in the tree view. 
                Customize card trees by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Card trees</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Card keywords" collapsed="true">
			<p><cref topic="creating_card_keywords">Card keywords</cref> are words, numbers or symbols that Mingle uses to create automatic links in cards and pages. When you're editing a card or page and you add any of these keywords, Mingle will automatically convert them to links. E.g. a card keyword of <strong>#</strong> lets you type <strong>#123</strong> to create a quick link to card 123. Customize card keywords by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Card keywords</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Favorites and tabs" collapsed="true">
			<p>You can setup <cref topic="creating_a_favorite_card_view">favorites</cref> for quick access to commonly used card views, and <cref topic="creating_tabs_from_favorites">turn the more common views into navigation tabs</cref>.</p>
			<p>Use the sample cards that came with the template to help setup your favorites. From within your project, setup favorites by clicking the <tab>All</tab> tab, then filter the card properties you want to view in the favorite. 
                Select <sidebar-button>Favorites</sidebar-button> on the right, and click on the <link>Add current view to team favorites...</link> link.</p>
			<screenshot alttext="Favorites sidebar button" src="resources/images/favorites_sidebar_button.png"/>
			<p>You can then <cref topic="creating_tabs_from_favorites">turn the favorite into a tab</cref> from the <link>Manage team favorites and tabs</link> in the Favorites sidebar panel.</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="Project variables" collapsed="true">
			<p><cref topic="project_variables">Project variables</cref> allow you to specify a value which can be referenced in many places within your Mingle project. 
        		Customize project variables by selecting <tab>Project admin</tab> tab, <link>Project variables</link> link.</p>
		</subsection>
	</section>
	<section title="Step three - Setup project reporting">
		<p>In Mingle, project reporting can be done via the <tab>Overview</tab> tab, <cref topic="working_with_pages">Mingle pages</cref> or cards. Here you can chart reports to see the status of your project and team workloads. 
        Since your project is based on a template, it will already include a few relevant <cref topic="creating_charts_and_tables_in_pages">graphs, tables and charts</cref> that you can customize. 
        	Mingle uses its own markup language called <cref topic="mql_reference">MQL</cref>, which you can use to create new reports.</p>
	</section>
	<section title="Step four - Add Mingle users and project team members" id='add_mingle_users_and_project_team_members'>
		<p>Once you're comfortable with your project settings, you can add users to Mingle and register them on your project.</p>
		<subsection title="To add new users">
			<p>To <cref topic="creating_user_profiles">add new users</cref>, click the <link>Manage users</link> link from the <strong>Current projects</strong> page (the first page you see after logging on - click the <strong>Mingle</strong> logo to display this page).</p>
			
			<info> Learn more about <cref topic="manage_users_page">managing users</cref>. </info>
			
		</subsection>
		<subsection title="To add team members to your project">
			<p>To add team members to a project, open your project from the All and click <tab>Project admin</tab> tab &gt; <link>Team</link>. </p>
		
		<info> Learn more about <cref topic="managing_project_team_members">managing project team members</cref>. </info>
		</subsection>
	</section>
	<section title="Step five - Clean up template items">
		<p>Since you created your project based on a template, there will be some items from the template that you won't use in your project. You should remove these before starting your project.</p>
		<bullets>
			<item>Each template contains a set of sample cards that you should remove. To remove these cards, click the <tab>All</tab> tab, select all cards and click the <button>Delete</button> button.</item>
			<item>Other items you may wish to remove include extra <cref topic="modifying_or_deleting_card_transitions">transitions</cref>, <cref topic="deleting_a_card_tree">card trees</cref>, 
                <cref topic="modifying_or_deleting_card_properties">card properties</cref>, <cref topic="managing_tags">tags</cref>, <cref topic="managing_favorites_and_tabs">favorites and tabs</cref>, 
                <cref topic="updating_card_keywords">card keywords</cref> and <cref topic="modifying_or_deleting_project_variables">project variables</cref>. 
                Click the <tab>Project admin</tab> tab to access each of these areas.</item>
		</bullets>
	</section>
	<section title="Step six - Start using Mingle">
		<p>See <cref topic="using_mingle">Using Mingle</cref> for details.</p>
	</section>
</topic>
