<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd"><topic title="Setting up quick header links">    <section title="Setting up quick header links">        <p>Header actions function as shortcuts to link to any page or saved view and to create new cards of any type. You can create header actions by <cref topic="creating_a_page">creating a page</cref> called <strong>Special:HeaderActions</strong>. These shortcuts display in the top part of your project's header, as in the following image:</p>        <screenshot alttext="Example header actions" src="resources/images/example_header_actions_new.png" />        <hint>          <bullets>            <item>To learn quick steps to create a special header, read our <cref topic="tip_special_headers">tips and tricks for special headers</cref> page.</item>            <item>There are no buttons or links for creating special header links - you set them up by creating a new page.</item>          </bullets>        </hint>    </section>    <section title="Obtaining URLs for quick header links">        <p>You do not have to type in the URLs for header actions from scratch, instead you can navigate to the content you want to link to and copy the URL from your browser. How to do this is explained in the sections below:</p>        <subsection title="URLs for pages">            <p>URLs for pages are simple - they are always in this format: <markup>/projects/project_identifier/wiki/<subst>page_name</subst></markup></p>            <bullets>                <item>Here <subst>page_name</subst> should be replaced by the canonicalized name for the page you are linking to, that is with all lowercase and spaces replaced by underscores (e.g. "My page" becomes "my_page").</item>                <item>and <subst>Link Name</subst> can be any text you wish to display in the header.</item>            </bullets>			 <p>To obtain the URL of a page, navigate to the page and copy the URL from your browser.</p>	    <bullets>	 <item>            <p><strong>Pages:</strong> <markup>/projects/project_identifier/wiki</markup> </p>            <p>This references the root page, which lists all pages in your Mingle project, and is also available in the <tab>Project admin</tab> tab <link>Pages</link> link.</p>        </item>        <item>            <p><strong>My work:</strong> <markup>/projects/project_identifier/wiki/My_Work</markup> </p>            <p>This references a user created page called 'My Work'. In this case the page could hold a table which uses the special value (current user) to present cards which are assigned to the currently logged in user.</p>        </item>    </bullets>  </subsection>        <subsection title="URLs for new cards">             <p>URLs for new cards are more complicated. The URLs to create a new card need to be in the following format:</p>                <p><markup>/projects/email_application/cards/new?properties[Type]=defect&amp;properties[Status]=new&amp;properties[Release]=R1</markup></p>                <p>This URL would create a card of type defect with a status of "new" in Release "R1". There are further examples below. </p> 			            <bullets>			                <item>			                    <p><strong>New bug:</strong> <markup>/projects/project_identifier/cards/new?properties[status]=new&amp;properties[type]=bug</markup></p>			                    <p>This action will create a new instance of a bug card, with the status property set to 'new' and open it for editing. The access key combination in Firefox would be <strong>Alt+Shift+b</strong></p>			                </item>			                <item>			                    <p><strong>New story:</strong> <markup>/projects/project_identifier/cards/new?properties[status]=new&amp;properties[type]=story</markup></p>			                    <p>This action will create a new instance of a story card, with the status property set to 'new' and open it for editing. The access key combination in Firefox would be <strong>Alt+Shift+s</strong></p>			                </item>			                <item>			                    <p><strong>New risk:</strong> <markup>/projects/project_identifier/cards/new?properties[status]=new&amp;properties[type]=risk</markup></p>			                    <p>This action will create a new instance of a risk card, with the status property set to 'new' and open it for editing. The access key combination in Firefox would be <strong>Alt+Shift+r</strong></p>			                </item>			            </bullets>        </subsection>        <subsection title="How to setup a quick header link">            <steps>                <item>Identify which quick header links you'd like to create and take a note of their URLs.</item>                <item>                    <p><cref topic="signing_in_and_out_of_mingle">Sign in</cref> to Mingle and open the project for which to add quick header links (if you're not already working in this project).</p>                    <note>You don't need to sign in as a project or Mingle administrator.</note>                </item>                <item>                    <p><strong>Navigate to the Special:HeaderActions page</strong>. In your browser's address bar, type <url>http://<subst>your_domain</subst>/projects/<subst>your_project_name</subst>/wiki/Special:HeaderActions</url> and press [Enter].                    Where <subst>your_domain</subst> is the location of Mingle in your organization and <subst>your_project_name</subst> is your project's name (i.e. the name Mingle assigns your project when first creating the project).                     If you currently have Mingle open you should be able to see this information in your browser's address bar.</p>                                        <p>Mingle displays a new blank page, (unless you've already created the Special:HeaderActions page previously, in which case you will need to hit the <link>Edit</link> link to edit the existing page)</p>                                </item>                <item>Type or paste the URLs for your quick links into this page.</item>                <item>                    <p>Click the <link>Save</link> link.</p>                    <p>Mingle displays the new quick header links at the top of your project page and creates a new page called Special:HeaderActions.</p>                </item>                <item>Test whether your new quick header links work as intended. If not, double-check the URLs and repeat.</item>            </steps>        </subsection>    </section>	<hint>If you want to see quick steps to create a special header, please take a look <cref topic="tip_special_headers">tips and tricks for special headers</cref> page.</hint>	</topic>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
