<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE section SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<section title="Git integration for Mingle Onsite" id="git">
  <subsection title="Before you start">
    <note>
      <bullets title="Please be aware:">
        <item><exref url="http://git-scm.com/">Git</exref> will need to be installed on the machine running Mingle. Please ensure that the directory containing your Git binaries is on your path. It is recommended that you use Git version 1.7.0 or higher.</item>
        <item>Using the Git source integration can take up extra disk space on the machine running Mingle. The amount of disk space used will be proportional to the size of the repository as well as the number of changesets. If you see any issues relating to limited disk space on the machine running Mingle please ensure you have adequate space for the Git source.   </item>
      </bullets>
    </note>
  </subsection>

  <subsection title="Configuration">
    <p>After successfully choosing <strong>Git</strong> from the source repository list, Mingle will display the <strong>Git repository settings</strong> page.</p>
    <screenshot alttext="Git Repository settings page" src="resources/images/git_repository_settings_page.png" />

    <bullets>
      <item>Enter the path that you wish to connect to.</item>
      <item>Enter the username/password to connect to the Git server. You must first click the <button>Change password</button> to enter a new password.</item>
    
      <screenshot alttext="Git repository settings page - user password" src="resources/images/git_repository_settings_password.png" />
    
      <item>Click the <link>Save settings</link> link to save the configuration</item>  
    </bullets>
  </subsection>

  <subsection title="Supported secure connections">
    <p>If you are serving Mingle via a secured connection, this plugin currently only work with SSL.  If you have configured your web server to only allow TLS connections, the plugin will not work.</p>
  </subsection>

</section>
