<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Signing in and out of Mingle">
	<section title="Introduction">	
		<p>You must sign in to Mingle before you can work on a project. 
			Your Mingle project administrator (or project manager) will give you the URL from where to access Mingle for your organization.</p>
		<p>Please note that your session will expire after four hours. Nor will Mingle require a password reset after a certain period of time.</p>
		
		<note>Before you can sign in to Mingle, a Mingle administrator must <cref topic="creating_user_profiles">add you as a user</cref>. 
			Then, before you can view any projects, a project administrator must <cref topic="managing_project_team_members">add you as a project team member</cref>.</note>
	</section>
	<section title="Signing in">		
		<p>To sign in to Mingle, type your username and password as advised by your Mingle administrator and click the <button>Sign in</button> button.</p>
		<screenshot alttext="Mingle sign in dialog" src="resources/images/new_login.png" />			
		<p>After signing in, Mingle displays all projects available to you or the overview page of the last visited project.
		If you can't see the project you want to access, ask your project administrator to grant you access as a team member.</p>
		<hint>After 10 failed login attempts, you will be prevented from making further attempts for some time.</hint>
	</section>
	<section title="Signing out">	
		<p>To sign out of Mingle, click the <link>Sign out</link> link at the top right of the page.</p>
		<screenshot alttext="Mingle sign out link" src="resources/images/sign_out.png"></screenshot>		
		<hint>Mingle may sign you out automatically after a certain amount of idle time as a security measure.</hint>
	</section>
	<section title="If you've forgotten your password?">	
		<p>On the Mingle Sign in page, click the <link>'Forgotten your password?'</link> link.</p>		
		<p>This displays the Recover your password page.</p>
			<screenshot alttext="Recover password page" src="resources/images/recover_password.png"></screenshot>
		<p>	Type your user name and click the <button>Recover password</button> button to send an email to the Mingle administrator(s) who will then reset your password and email you when this has been done. The Mingle administrator details were setup during <cref topic="completing_the_mingle_configuration_wizard">initial installation</cref>. Mingle administrators can manage user details from the <strong>Current projects</strong> page <link>Manage users</link> link.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section title="Also see...">	
		<bullets>
			<item><cref topic="user_roles">About Mingle user roles</cref></item>
			<item><cref topic="managing_your_user_profile">Managing your user profile</cref></item>
		</bullets>
	</section>
</topic>