<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2020 ThoughtWorks, Inc.

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "mingle_help.dtd">
<topic title="Updating cards in bulk">
    <section title="Introduction">
    	<p>From the card <cref topic="list_view">List view</cref>, you can select multiple cards for bulk updates.</p>    	
    	<bullets title="Once you've selected the cards you want to update, you can">
	    	 <item>delete the cards</item>
	    	 <item>update card properties</item>
	    	 <item>apply a <cref topic="card_transitions">card transition</cref></item>
	    	 <item>add or remove tags</item>
    	</bullets>
    </section>
	
	<section title="How to update multiple cards at once">
		<steps>
			<item><cref topic="signing_in_and_out_of_mingle">Sign in</cref> to Mingle and open the project with the cards you want to update (if not already working in the project).</item>
			<item>Open a <cref topic="list_view">list view</cref>, the default <tab>All</tab> tab is a good place to start if there are no more specific tabs to choose.</item>
			<item>
				<p><cref topic="filter_list_by_component">Locate the cards</cref> you want to update.</p>
				<p><screenshot alttext="List view - page header controls highlighted" src="resources/images/list_view_select_cards.png" /></p>
			</item>			
			<item><strong>Select the cards</strong> you want to update by clicking the checkbox next to each card. You can click the <link>All</link> link or the <link>None</link> link to select or deselect all cards on the page.</item>
			<item>
				<p>
					The 'All' checkbox by default will select all cards that exist on the current page that you are viewing. 
					After selecting 'All' you will also be presented with a link to select all of the cards in the entire view (across all pages). 
					Clicking this link will select all of the cards in the entire view and make those cards available for bulk operations.
				</p>
				<p><screenshot alttext="List view - select all cards in current view" src="resources/images/list_view_select_all_cards_in_view.png" /></p>
			</item>			
			<item>Clicking 'None' at any time will de-select all cards on the current page or view (whichever is applicable).</item>
		</steps>
		<subsection title="Deleting cards" file="deleting_a_card" collapsed="false"/>
		<subsection title="Tagging">
			<p>To add, edit or remove tags attached to cards, click the <button>Tag</button> button.</p>
			<p>Mingle displays any current tags for the selected card(s) and lets you add more.</p>
			<screenshot alttext="List view - update multiple tags" src="resources/images/update_multiple_tags.png" />		
			<p>If you'd like to remove tags from the selected card(s), simply click the X next to the tag.</p>
			<p>To tag the selected cards, type the tag name(s) and click the <button>Add tags</button> button. (Separate tags with commas.)</p>
			<p>You can close the tags control by clicking on the <button>Close</button> button. Don't forget to save any new tags before you close the control.</p>
		</subsection>
		
		<subsection title="Updating properties">
			<p>To update card property values for the selected cards, click the <button>Edit properties</button> button.</p>
			<screenshot alttext="List view - update multiple property values" src="resources/images/edit_multiple_properties.png"></screenshot>
		
			<p>Mingle displays all card properties setup for the project.</p>
			<p>Click the name of the card property you want to update and select the property value.</p>
			<warning>
				If you have selected cards of different types, then Mingle will display <strong>Type (mixed value)</strong>.
				If you change this value - you will be changing the type of the selected cards to the new value. 
				This action will lose data from any properties that are not shared between the original card types and the new card type.
				You should carefully consider the consequences of doing this, as the changes are not recoverable.
				<p><screenshot alttext="Warning - changing card type" src="resources/images/bulk_edit_mixed_card_types.png"></screenshot></p>
			</warning>
		</subsection>
		
		<subsection title="Applying transitions">
			<p>To apply a transition, select an option from the menu at the top of the list.</p>	
			<p><screenshot alttext="List view - apply a transition" src="resources/images/bulk_edit_apply_transition.png"></screenshot></p>
			<p>Mingle updates the selected cards' properties according to the way the <cref topic="creating_card_transitions">transition is setup</cref>.</p>
			<note>Mingle only displays the option to apply transitions if one or more selected cards <cref topic="card_transitions">meet the conditions for a transition</cref></note>.
		</subsection>


    </section>
</topic>


